AHRIM HAN, PH.D.

□ ahrimhan@gmail.com □ ahrimhan.github.io □ (949)910-8751

♥ 913 Piccolo, Irvine, CA, 92620 (Permanent Resident and Eligible to Work in the U.S)

in ahrimhan O ahrimhan

SUMMARY

I am working to transit from academia to industry to work as a data scientist. Over 14 years, I have researched software engineering in computer science for improving software design and code quality using statistics and machine learning techniques. During my research days, I focused on software-related problems. Now I have special interests to solve user-related problems such as user preference prediction by leveraging big data intelligence.

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) · Feb. 2007 to Aug. 2013

Ph.D. Computer Science 2013

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) · Sept. 2004 to Feb. 2007

M.S. Computer Science 2007

Sogang UniversityFeb. 2000 to Feb. 2004 B.E. Computer Science 2004 Magna Cum Laude

PROJECTS

Sentimental Analysis of Movie Reviews using a Deep Learning Neural Network (Springboard) Mar. 2019 to June 2019

We have developed a deep learning model to automatically classify movie reviews as positive or negative in Python with Keras. We especially identify and deal with overfitting and use a pre-trained embedding in a neural network model to improve accuracy.

Prediction of Scores for Public Schools in California (Springboard) · Oct. 2018 to June 2019

I applied many of the data science-related techniques for data wrangling, exploratory data analysis, data visualization, and machine learning modeling. I provided the prediction models using the regression and classification algorithms for finding the inferior schools that need help.

Efficient Refactoring Candidate Identification (Korea University) · Mar. 2008 to Apr. 2017

I developed an efficient refactoring candidate recommendation system that helps software developers change code more easily. The main challenge is the heavy computation for evaluating large refactoring candidates, therefore, I developed the following methods in order to increase computational efficiency.

- I developed the fast graph-based coupling metric for calculating the effects of suggested refactorings based on matrix computation. This sacrifices some degree of precision but significantly reduces the computation complexity, which can be helpful in analyzing large-scale software.
- I suggested the two-phased search-based refactoring identification method for reducing the search space of the candidates by predicting refactoring candidates with higher chances of quality improvement. Compared to the no-reduction approach, the two-phased refactoring identification approach is 2.6 (min) to 13.5 (max) times faster in computation time.

Improvement of Change-Proneness Prediction (KAIST) · Mar. 2006 to Feb. 2010

I developed a more accurate change-proneness prediction model to help software developers to focus their efforts on more critical maintenance activities. I developed the new behavioral dependency metrics that capture the dynamic aspects of the program. Using dependency metrics in conjunction with existing program structural metrics, we built the regression model for change-proneness prediction. The accuracy (R-square) of our model is increased 8% than the model using only structural metrics.

EXPERIENCE

Springboard
Data Science Career Track - Student · Oct. 2018 to Current

- Mastering skills in Python, SQL, data wrangling, data visualization, exploratory data analysis, and machine learning methods
- Performed two data science related capstone projects: "Prediction of Scores for Public Schools in California" and "Sentimental Analysis of Movie Reviews using a Deep Learning Neural Network"

Korea University Research Professor · Seoul, South Korea · Sept. 2013 to Apr. 2018

- Advised graduate students to develop research topics and conduct the experiments
- Awarded the major national grants for my research projects, "Efficient Refactoring Candidate Identification" (role: Principal Investigator) (Received \$125,000 and \$33,000 from the National Research Foundation of Korea)
- Published the research results in the top conferences and journals such as IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering (Google Scholar)

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) Graduate Researcher · Daejeon, South Korea · Mar. 2005 to Aug. 2013

- Actively performed my research project "Improvement of Change-Proneness Prediction" (papers cited 64 times)
- Mentoring and Taught in Computer Science courses: "Introduction to JAVA programming" and "Capstone Projects in CS"
- Implemented program structure analysis and metric measurement tools using Java and Python

Peace Corps (Headquarters)
Intern · Washington D.C, USA · Aug. 2004 to Oct. 2004

Responsible for organizing the intranet web pages in the Technical Infrastructure and Support Team under the Chief Information Officer

SKILLS

DATA ANALYSIS, VISUALIZATION, AND PREDICTIVE MODELING: Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Pyplot, Seaborn, Scikit-Learn, Keras, Tensorflow, PySpark STATISTICAL METHODS AND MACHINE LEARNING: Classification, Regression, Clustering, Hypothesis Testing, Deep Learning PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND TOOLS: Python, SQL, Java, R, Fortran, Assembly, Markdown, Latex, SPSS RESEARCH AREAS: Software Engineering, Refactoring, Software Quality Improvement, Software Design Measurement